

# **Olivier Penhoat**

Full stack engineer, CTO

#### About me

I am passionate about **web development**, **experienced** in team management and coaching, able to create a **digital platform** from Think stage, to Build, Devops and Run.

CTO resolutely craftsman, capable of developing and carrying a real product vision.

In my favorite playground we often find: *JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Jest, REST, GraphQL, Docker, Redis, MongoDb, ReactJS, Zsh, Portainer, Traefik* 

#### Bio

Age

50

**☑** Email

openhoat@gmail.com

City

Bordeaux, France

# Skills

NodeJS

EXPERT
JavaScript / TypeScript
EXPERT
Docker / K8s
MASTER MASTER
ReactJS
COMFORTABLE
AngularJS
COMFORTABLE
VueJS
FAMILIAR PARTICIPATION OF THE PROPERTY OF THE
Redis
COMFORTABLE
MongoDB
COMFORTABLE
Réseaux de neurones / Machine Learning
COMFORTABLE
Shell
MASTER MASTER
REST
MASTER
GraphQL
MASTER
HTML 5
MASTER
CSS 3
FAMILIAR

COMFORTABLE

Markdown

**MASTER** 

**Jest** 

**EXPERT** 

Python, Go

FAMILIAR

### Experience

Ohief Technical Officer at Niji Bordeaux

2021

- · Coaching of ReactJS front dev teams
- Development of a NodeJS / MongoDb / NestJS REST API backend to collect Covid tests
- Mise en oeuvre de pipelines Azure de build et de déploiement
- Management and coordination of a BNP Leasing Solutions selfcare API project
- Support for technical interviews of candidates

CTO / Product Owner / Full stack engineer at Groupe La Poste / Branche Numérique

2015 - 2021

- Migration of the API gateway to TypeScript
- · Design and implementation of the Digiposte authentication gateway
- Creation of the CN23 mobile web application for customs declaration on tablet
- Creation of the Okapi platform, Open API of the Digital Branch of La Poste Group (developer.laposte.fr)
- · Definition of the roadmap and business models
- Integration of billing solution, limiters, plugins
- BU Management: agile team, vision box
- Open innovation advocate
- · Al training / fundamental neural networks
- Conferences / practice / katas

- API expertise: publication of white paper API design and training
- Stack: EcmaScript, TypeScript, GraphQL, Reactjs, Webpack, Expressjs, Gitlab pipeline, Docker, ELK, Redis

#### IT Architect at Groupe La Poste / Branche Numérique

2014 - 2015

- IT Architecture for Digital Confidence (Digiposte, Digiposte Pass)
- Implementations of some POCs, intra consulting
- Management of the Open API POC project for the Group
- Implementation of the laposte.io
- Full stack expertise

#### Consultant at Octo Technology

2013

- Technical architecture at Digiposte
- · Validation of technical choices
- Coordination of performance tests
- Implementation of prototypes
- Coding of an URL shortener service for Octo
- Coding of a Dropbox / Digiposte synch webapp

#### Consultant Trainer chez Valtech Training

2009 - 2013

- Training on over twenty courses J2EE, JS, Web, Factory Software, Quality, Security
- Areas of industry, insurance banking, service: Thalès, Dassault, NDS, Generali, CDC, Orange, ...
- R&D: Java Quality, Android, Mobile Web, Web Hacking, NodeJS, Extreme Java
- Technical coaching
- Seminars: Android, Cross-platform development, NodeJS
- · Design and production of the desktop and mobile website valtech-training.fr
- Implementation of the software factory

#### O Software factory chief chez Le Crédit Lyonnais

- Management of a support and assistance team for tech people
- Implementation of changes in the LCL software factory
- Study on the exportability of the software factory in offshore projects
- · Animation of working groups around SOA, WOA, REST
- New services and bank products chief at Crédit Agricole S.A.

2005 - 2008

- Project management Coordination of Multiple Access Banking and Mobile Internet projects
- Definition of product plans, animation of technical committees, realization of POCs, participation in Architecture Working Groups
- BAM projects, electronic statement, electronic signature, iPhone site
- RESTful SSO solution reengineering
- Technology solutions projects chief at Entenial

2001 - 2005

- Operational supervision of Web developers within the "multi-channel" pole
- Developer training in Java / Beanshell / Taglib / JSTL / MVC2
- Participation in construction work, and assistance to MOA
- Technical project chief chez MDEO-Zentropy

2000 - 2001

- Operational supervision of web projects
- · Creation of the nabab.fr website
- Design and realization of an ORM
- iNet technologies consultant at Cetal Conseil

1999 - 2000

- Advising banks (Crédit Agricole, CCF, Société Générale) in the field of iNet technologies
- Training of internal teams in web development
- Redesign of the BancoPC site (www.ccf.fr) at a fixed price

### Online banking project chief chez Crédit Commercial de France

1999 - 2000

- Project management of Distance Banking projects within IT Studies
- Projects: BancoPC, WAP, Webroker
- Changeover to the Euro, a 2000
- C Engineer chez Isthme / Steria

1994 - 1996

Development of telematics and client / server applications in the banking and tertiary sector

## Education

Engineer Epita Paris

1993

Industrial computer science and artificial intelligence

O BTS Lycée Jules Ferry de Versailles

1991

Industrial computer science

Bac Lycée Jules Ferry de Versailles

1989

F2 Électronique (mention bien)

## Contact

□ openhoat@gmail.com